# DALTON C. OKECHUKWU (M.Eng)

Software Engineer (Javascript | Typescript | Python | Java)

Mobile: +1 (825) 365-4540 | Web: https://www.dalton-web.dev

E-mail: dalton.0x0@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daltonokechukwu

GitHub: https://github.com/dalton-0x0

#### Profile

Creative engineer with a holistic approach to software development and a track record of delivering seamless user experience via clean code that is performant, reliable, secure and in line with SOLID principles. Experienced in architecting software systems for enterprise applications including dashboarding and compliance management tools that provide valuable analytical insights for clients. Mainly utilizes the conventional MERN stack (Mongo, Express, React, Node) for full stack development, with hobbyist projects written in other programming languages like Python and Java.

#### Skills

- Frontend (Typescript, React)
- Backend (Node, Django)
- Testing (Jest, Mocha)
- Databases (SQL, MongoDB)
- Algorithms (Python)
- Serverless (AWS, Firebase)
- Deployment (Jenkins, Circle CI)
- API Development
- Containerization (Docker)

#### Projects

- <u>Certification Automation by Onetrust</u>: software that streamlines the compliance certification process from readiness health-checks to evidence collection (including using third party integrations), risk identification and the actual audit report generation.
- DeepSea by White Whale: dashboarding and data visualization web application that utilizes AI tools for
  predictive analysis, pattern recognition, and data modeling. Allows users to either use built-in algorithms or
  upload custom ones.
- <u>Ecommerce Website</u>: fully functional apparel store with authentication, cart and payment at checkout. An intuitive and responsive design for both web and mobile platforms using Node/Express, React/Redux, Firebase for authentication and session management, Stripe for payment processing.
- <u>Al Facial Recognition</u>: fun Al tool using a gRPC model that returns a bounded box over the area with the highest probability of containing a human face using React, NodeJS and Clarifai api.
- Robot friends: a fun app that maintains state using React. Random robot images are fetched using the Robohash api, usernames are parsed from a JSON placeholder.
- Transformations Game [ <u>source code</u>]: math learning game for 7th graders sponsored by the Calgary Board of Education.
- Weather App [source code]: weather app that fetches data from an API and displays results on the screen, designed using NodeJS/Express (backend) and Mustache/Handlebars templates for the frontend.

### Employment

# Software Engineer, Frontend OneTrust Canada Inc [Canada]

2021-Date

- Collaborates with product management, UI/UX and QA to determine feasibility of new features by evaluating requirements and scopes work into user stories.
- Updates coding standards and documentation.
- Maintains tech debt backlog and drives completion of open items.
- Implements test-driven development, prioritizes bug fixes for optimal user experience.
- Deputizes as engineering team lead.

### Software Developer, Full Stack White Whale Analytics [Canada]

2019 -2021

- Translates wireframes and design mock-ups to functional user interface.
- Builds reusable react components using redux for app-wide state management.
- Employs test driven development for the maintenance of frontend and backend microservices.
- Manages backend routes, controllers, and models within microservices using Node and HapiJS.

# Full-Stack Developer

# EvolveU [Canada]

2018- 2019

- Uses JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML/CSS, Python, Flask, PostgreSQL to builds complete web applications from front-end design to back-end server and database architecture and deployment.
- Uses test-driven development practices for fast development of highly maintainable code with fewer bugs.

#### Production Engineering Manager

#### Water Analytics [United States]

2016 - 2019

- Designs architecture and implements new features for electrochemical devices.
- Writes scripts, manages testing programs and debugging tasks.
- Manages all software upgrades.

# Education

## **University of Massachusetts**

M.Eng | B.EngGraduate Certificate

Mechanical Engineering Chemical Engineering Design and Manufacturing Process Simulation and Control

#### **Amazon Web Services**

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect (in progress)

#### Research

- Analysis of Gravity Driven Flow in a Simple Tank and Pipe System.
- Xenon-Iodine Dynamics for Nuclear Facilities.
- Economic Analysis of Dimethyl Ether Production Plant.